In this clip we are going to talk to you about the common mistakes that players will make.
We are talking about all levels.
Club players sometimes, even tournament players in their first move to the ball.
A lot of players will just shuffle to the ball, making them a lot slower and they do not get their rotation, and by the time they get to the ball they are playing catch-up.
So watch this.
This is the common mistake.
See how he is shuffling to the ball, he cannot get in position, does not get his feet organized to the ball, and he is doing the crab walk.
It does not even look good.
So now we will show you what you want to do, as opposed to that.
The movement is that the first move has to be a step out, your right foot is going to come out of the forehand side, you are getting your rotation, and then you can officially run to the ball and not shuffle to the ball.
So we will see what he does right here.
His first move, he is stepping out and then he runs.
He turns his upper body right away, he runs over.
Step out, and then the run.
See that, a lot quicker.
He is going to be able to get there a lot earlier, and when you are there early, you have options.
That is very, very important right there.